# **Jeff Liang**

Authorized to work in the United States Willing to relocate

Phone: (626)456-2859

Email: jeff.c.liang@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-c-liang

Website: www.jeffliang.us

I am a software engineer who is currently working at a subsidiary of AT&T called Fullscreen, where primarily working on internal tools using javascript. 3 years of experience building web applications in JavaScript (React, Redux), HTML5, and CSS3. Prior to his recent three years spent working on front-end web development, he also spent three years as a mechanical engineer designing suspension components for Honda, where he gained substantial experience in 3D CAD design.

### **SKILLS**

- ◆ JavaScript/ES6 (React, Redux, Three.js)
- ◆ CSS3 (Sass), Bootstrap
- ◆ HTML5
- ◆ Ruby on Rails

- ◆ Git
- ◆ AWS (ECS, CodePipeline)
- ♦ Jira
- ◆ 2D/3D CAD design, Catia

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer - Fullscreen, Los Angeles, CA

Aug 2019 - now

Implement awesome features on internal tools with PM, designers, backend team, and QA engineers.

## FS Connect | Ruby on rails, React-Rails, Bootstrap

Create a credential management tool to enable the data engineering team to retrieve YouTube analytics data via the Reporting API.

- Build UI components(forms, sortable tables) in Rails. Use React-Rails for state management on modal, table editing, etc.
- Write model, controller methods to update the business logic and pass the data to view files.
- Use git cherry-pick to expedite development process and git rebase to keep git history organized.
- Customize UI systematically by updating bootstrap variables instead of adding one off styling.
  Provide technical advice to designers for UI/UX design.
- Generate test cases, update dummy users for different testing scenarios with backend and QA engineers.

# HUB | React, Redux, AVA/Cypress, Storybook

Implement new features on an existing internal tool for influencer managers to create action items, track talent earnings, payments, and channel detail.

- Implement Restful APIs for new features with backend engineers.
- Build UI/UX components in React (dashboard, fix column tables), organize state in Redux.
- Writing unit tests, component tests in AVA and end to end tests in Cypress.
- Process bug reports from Honeybadger and release bug fixes.
- Refactor code to improve code maintainability. Create and re-use functions for similar blocks of code. Reduce remediation time from 2,203 hours to 1,446 hours(35%).

## Creator Platform | Rails, Angular

A consumer-facing product for influencers to track their earnings, update personal(payment) information, and provide access to awesome tools to improve their videos/post.

- Migrated an angular tool into Rails land. Handle UI behavior in vanillaJS.
- Generated migration files to update database schema.
- Work with designers for UI design. Provide technical feedback for dryer, reusable components.
- Using AWS ecs tools to update testing cases data on the feature environment database to expedite verification process.

### Software Engineer - KLA, San Jose, CA

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Develop, engage and promote global enterprise solutions leading the way with innovations which meet the business' needs.

## Unified Issue Tracker | React(hooks), ANTD, Sharepoint API

Created a web tool for stakeholders to easily track and assign action items.

- Integrated product issue data from 3 different sources to Sharepoint List.
- Worked agility with stakeholders for UI implementation.
- Used React hooks for UI component state management.
- Built email notification feature in Microsoft-Flow.
- Worked on web accessibility across browsers include IE.

## Mechanical Engineer - FTech R&D NA, Troy, Ohio

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017

Developed Honda CRV 2018 and Acura MDX 2020 suspension parts from prototype validation to mass production. Applied **object-oriented** design to lower the development cost near 50%.

### Mechanical Engineer - Trouve, Taipei, Taiwan

May 2015 - Agu 2015

Designed powertrain components for an EV prototype. Work with control and battery teams for vehicle layout design, and strength/durability simulation.

#### Mechanical Engineer - Honda of America Manufacturing, Anna, Ohio

Jun 2014 - Apr 2015

Designed jigs and fixtures to improve production line ergonomic, efficiency, quality, and cost. Applied modular design to lower the development and maintainability cost.

#### **EDUCATION**

**App Academy** Full, stack web development bootcamp

Feb 2018 - May 2018

Wright State University MS - Mechanical Engineering

Class of 2016